Guide to the Papers of George L. Mosse (1918-1999), 1780-2001 AR 25137 / MF 671
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series III: Correspondence, 1919-2001; 22 linear feet
  - Subseries 3: Personal, undated, 1946-2001; 9 linear feet
    - B) Individuals
      - Wurgaft, Lewis D., 1970-1978, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 31)
      - Yack, Bernard, 1996? (Box 40, Folder 32)
      - Yahil, Leni, 1978, 1982, 1998 (Box 40, Folder 33)
      - Zabel, Hans-Henning, undated, 1966-1988 (Box 40, Folder 34)
      - Zammito, John H., 1983 (Box 40, Folder 35)
      - Zani, Luciano, 1995, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 36)
      - Zapponi, Niccolò, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 37)
      - Zerubavel, Yael, 1992-1996 (Box 40, Folder 38)
      - Ziege, Eva-Maria, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 39)
      - Zimmermann, Mosche, 1978-1998 (Box 40, Folder 40)
      - Zipes, Jack David, 1980, 1988-1996 (Box 40, Folder 41)
  - Subseries 4: Professional - Institutions and Organizations, 1945-2001; 6.5 linear feet
    Alphabetical by name of institution.
    This subseries is comprised of correspondence that George L. Mosse had with various organizations. In general two major areas stand out. One is correspondence with publishers and publishing houses both in the United States and abroad. The other group is made up of educational institutions, mostly universities and foundations that were interested in George L. Mosse's lectures or some form of collaboration. The final products of George L. Mosse's activities can be found in other series, most notably in Series II: Writings and Research, where both his texts and drafts of lectures and articles are located. The invitations to the lectures that were rejected or ignored are filed in General correspondence. When George L. Mosse reacted upon the offer the letter exchanges are usually filed in a separate file under the institution's name.
    The institutions on which faculty George L. Mosse served for extended periods of time have material that also reflect the functioning of the department or university, as it is the case of the (State) University of Iowa where George L. Mosse taught between the years 1944-1955, the University of Wisconsin(1955-1988) or Hebrew University(as Koebner Professor 1979-1986). The correspondence with a great number of universities where George L. Mosse acted as a visiting professor provides valuable information about his academic pursuits as well.
    Letters between George L. Mosse and publishers of his works - either books or articles - constitute the other large part of this subseries. The most prominent seems to be correspondence with Howard Fertig with whose publishing firm George L. Mosse maintained a relationship for more than a quarter of the century. It was Fertig's company that published Germans and Jews,Nationalism and Sexuality, and Masses and Men. The relationship was not strictly merely professional, but many of the letters give away many details of George L. Mosse' academic career, i.e. deadlines for books, articles George L. Mosse was about to write, conferences he was about to attend etc. The correspondence with publishing houses is not restricted only to the process of publication, but often contains various documents that pertain to the text production. The folder of the Japanese publishing house Kashiwa Shobō contains also communications with translators of George Mosse's books and pertains to other Japanese translations of his works as well. Among the publishing companies that put out George L. Mosse's books belong Athenäum-Verlag(Nazi Alltag,Ein Volk, ein Reich, ein Führer),Beltz Verlag,Campus Verlag,Società editrice il Mulino(Italian publisher of Nationalization of the Masses),Ullstein(Nationalisierung der Massen),Verlag Anton Hain(Völkische Revolution,Der nationalsozialistische Alltag), and many university presses in the United States. Besides these companies many professional academic associations often published George Mosse's texts, most notably articles, as for instance the Association for the Study of Ethnicity and Nationalism (ASEN).
    George L. Mosse was an editor of a Rand McNally history series in the 1960s and his correspondence with Rand McNally Company contains letters written in both of his capacities as an author and editor. Theodore D. Tieken and Jack Carr were editors of the publishing house.
    George L. Mosse's interest and involvement in Jewish studies and historical genesis of fascism and Nazism lead to his closer association with such institutions as the Leo Baeck Institute in London and New York, the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, where George L. Mosse was appointed as the first scholar in residence, and several other mostly Jewish institutions in Germany, the United States, and elsewhere. Later when his scholarly focus shifted to studies of sexuality, he participated often in international conferences and other undertakings that explored the questions of sexual identity in historical context.
    Next to the United States and Israel, Italy was another country where George L. Mosse exercised a considerable intellectual influence. His frequent interviews in Italian periodicals both scholarly and non-academic are in Series I: Personal, Subseries 1: General, but George L. Mosse's correspondence with publishing houses, editors or research institutions can be found in this subseries.
    George L. Mosse was a committed educator who always stressed importance of teaching and meeting with students. A reduction of his teaching responsibilities by 50 per cent was the reason why he refused a Villas Professorship, an honor reserved for only the most distinguished professor at the University of Wisconsin. George L. Mosse did not restrain himself to teaching at the University of Wisconsin, but he lectured extensively at universities and associations in the United States and abroad from Poland to South Africa to Australia and this subseries documents his pedagogical determination well.
    - A) General
      - Articles - Rejected, 1980-1981, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 42)
      - Confronting the Nation- Copyright and Reprint Requests, 1990-1993 (Box 40, Folder 43)
      - Holy Pretence- Negotiations with Publishers, 1953-1956 (Box 40, Folder 44)
      - Invitations to Speak, 1968-1997 (Box 40, Folder 45)
      - Job Inquiries, 1966-1968 (Box 40, Folder 46)
      - Lectures, 1968-1984 (Box 40, Folder 47)
      - Lectures and Conferences - Rejected, 1976-1984 (Box 40, Folder 48)
      - Nazi Culture- Copyright and Reprint Requests, 1969-1998 (Box 40, Folder 49)
      - Syllabi - Reactions, 1948-1951 (Box 40, Folder 50)
      - Western Civilisation - Core Course, 1946-1951 (Box 40, Folder 51)
      - Western Civilization Source Book - Reprint Requests, 1945-1947 (Box 40, Folder 52)
    - B) Individual Institutions
      - Abbeville Press, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 53)
      - Accademia di studi storici Aldo Moro, 1978-1983, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 54)
      - Agence Sialtiel, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 55)
      - Akademie der Künste (Berlin, Germany), 1997 (Box 40, Folder 56)
      - Aldus Books, 1967-1971 (Box 40, Folder 57)
      - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1950, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 58)
      - Alice-Salomon-Fachhochschule, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 59)
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1984-1994 (Box 40, Folder 60)
      - American Association of Teachers of German, 1998 (Box 40, Folder 61)
      - American Civil Liberties Union, 1992-1998 (Box 40, Folder 62)
      - American Committee on the History of the Second World, 1967-1974 (Box 40, Folder 63)
      - American Council for Judaism, 1979-1980 (Box 40, Folder 64)
      - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 65)
      - American Historical Association, 1948-1990 (Box 40, Folder 66)
      - American Historical Association - Awards and Honors, 1996-1998 (Box 40, Folder 67)
      - American Historical Association - George L. Mosse Prize, 2000-2001 (Box 40, Folder 68)
      - American Historical Association. Committee on Gay and Lesbian History, 1986-1989, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 69)
      - American Historical Association. Modern European History Section. Executive Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 70)
      - American Historical Review, 1971, 1973, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 71)
      - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 72)
      - American Jewish Archives, 1987-1990 (Box 40, Folder 73)
      - American Jewish Committee, 1972-1998 (Box 40, Folder 74)
      - American Philosophical Society, 1966, 1968, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 75)
      - American Political Science Review, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 76)
      - American Society of Church History, 1953, 1969-1974 (Box 40, Folder 77)
      - Amerika Haus (Frankfurt am Main, Germany), 1995 (Box 40, Folder 78)
      - Amerika Haus - Various Cities, 1951-1956 (Box 40, Folder 79)
      - Amherst College, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 80)
      - Andere Welt, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 81)
      - Angestelltenkammer Bremen, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 82)
      - Anglo-American Conference of Historians, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 83)
      - Anne Frank Institute of Philadelphia, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 84)
      - Anthrozoös, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 85)
      - Anti-Defamation League, 1985-1989 (Box 40, Folder 86)
      - Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 1982-1998 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Aronoff Foundation, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Association for the Study of Etnicity and Nationalism, 1993-1995 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Athenäum-Verlag, 1977-1987 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Australian National University, 1983-1988 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Authors' Guild (U.S.), 1994 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Autorenbuchhandlung, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Basic Inquiry, 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - BasicBooks, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Beltz Verlag (Weinheim an der Bergstrasse, Germany), 1995-1998 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Berlin Museum, 1987-1994 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Berlinische Galerie, 1984-1989, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Blackwell Publishers, 1956-1984 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Das Blättchen, 1997-1998 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Brooklyn College, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - Brooklyn Museum, 1939-1942, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Broom Street Theater, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Cambridge University Press, 1957-1961, 1990-1997 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Camera dei Depuitati. Archivo Storico (Rome, Italy), 1998 (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - Campus Verlag, 1990-1998 (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Carl Hanser Verlag, 1985-1998 (Box 41, Folder 22)
      - Carthage College (Kenosha, Wis.), 1968-1970 (Box 41, Folder 23)
      - Carthage College (Kenosha, Wis.) - Doctor of Literature, honoris causa, Degree, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 24)
      - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, Calif.), 1969-1972 (Box 41, Folder 25)
      - Center for Documentary Media - Robert J. Lifton Documentary Series, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - Center for Millennial Studies (Boston, Mass.), 1998 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - Central European History, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 28)
      - Centre national de la recherche scientifique (France), 1998 (Box 41, Folder 29)
      - Centro di Ricerca e Documentazione Febbraio'74, 1979-1992 (Box 41, Folder 30)
      - Chicago Gay and Lesbian Project, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 31)
      - Cinnabar Pictures, 1996-1998 (Box 41, Folder 32)
      - Clark University (Worcester, Mass.), 1982-1983 (Box 41, Folder 33)
      - Cleveland State University, 1982-1983 (Box 41, Folder 34)
      - CLIO, 1979, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 35)
      - College of Wooster. Jewish Student Association, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 36)
      - Columbia University Press, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 37)
      - Commission for the Clarification of Nazi Activities in the Argentine Republic, 1997-1998 (Box 41, Folder 38)
      - Conference on British Studies, 1953-1960 (Box 41, Folder 39)
      - Congregation Sinai (Milwaukee, Wis.), 1975 (Box 41, Folder 40)
      - Consortium for the Study of Society and Education, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 41)
      - Contemporary Authors, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 42)
      - Cornell University, 1988-1999 (Box 41, Folder 43)
      - Cornell University. Mario Einaudi Center for International Studies, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 44)
      - Cornell University Press, 1989, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 45)
      - Corriere Della Serra, 1986-1992 (Box 41, Folder 46)
      - Croom Helm Publishers, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 47)
      - Culturefront, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 48)
      - Czytelnik (Firm), 1976, 1982-1986 (Box 41, Folder 49)
      - Danforth Foundation (Saint Louis, Mo.), 1968-1969 (Box 41, Folder 50)
      - Danforth Foundation (Saint Louis, Mo.) - Harbison Prize, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 51)
      - Dartmouth College - Conference, 1994-1995 (Box 41, Folder 52)
      - Deutsche Gesellschaft für Natur- und Völkerkunde, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 53)
      - Deutsche Historiker-Gesellschaft, 1960-1962 (Box 41, Folder 54)
      - Deutscher Taschenbuch Verlag (dtv), 1983-1985 (Box 41, Folder 55)
      - Di Renzo Editore, 1997-1998 (Box 41, Folder 56)
      - Dietz Verlag, 1991-1992 (Box 41, Folder 57)
      - Dryden Press (Box 41, Folder 58)
      - Duke University, 1967, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 59)
      - École des hautes études en sciences sociales. Centre de recherches historiques, 1986 (Box 41, Folder 60)
      - Edgewood College, 1992-1995 (Box 41, Folder 61)
      - Edward Arnold (Publishers), 1979-1982 (Box 41, Folder 62)
      - Editori Laterza, 1975-1989 (Box 41, Folder 63)
      - Editori Laterza, 1990-1998 (Box 41, Folder 64)
      - Editrice la Giuntina, 1988-1996 (Box 41, Folder 65)
      - Elvehjem Museum of Art, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 66)
      - Encyclopedia of the Holocaust, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 67)
      - Encyclopedia of Violence in the United States, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 68)
      - Etruria Oggi, 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 69)
      - Field Enterprises Educational Corporation, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 70)
      - Florida International University, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 71)
      - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1958-1959 (Box 41, Folder 72)
      - Fondazione Giangiacomo Feltrinelli, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 73)
      - Fondazione Giovanni Agnelli, 1985-1986 (Box 41, Folder 74)
      - Fondazione Il Vittoriale degli Italiani, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 75)
      - Fondazione Istituto Gramsci, 1996 (Box 41, Folder 76)
      - Fondazione Sandro Penna, 1984-1991 (Box 41, Folder 77)
      - Fondazione "Spadolini-Nuova antologia", 1996-1998 (Box 41, Folder 78)
      - Forward, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 79)
      - Freie Universität Berlin, 1982-1998 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Friedrich-Naumann-Stiftung, 1983-1987 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Fritz Thyssen Stiftung, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Gage Educational Publishing Limited, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Gay Activists Alliance, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Gerhard-Mercator-Universität Gesamthochschule Duisburg, 1983, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - German Historical Institute (Washington, D.C.), 1988? (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - German Literature, Art and Thought, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - German Studies Association, 1992-1998 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Giulio Einaudi editore, 1995-1997 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - Goethe House New York, 1977-1978 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Goethe-Institut (Munich, Germany) - Goethe-Medaille, 1987-1988 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Goethe Institute Ann Harbor, 1991-1992 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - Goethe Institute Jerusalem, 1981, 1987, 1995 (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - Goethe Institute Rome, 1989-1998 (Box 42, Folder 16)
      - Gratz College (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1986 (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - Grosset & Dunlap - Crisis of German Ideology, 1962-1979 (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - Grosset & Dunlap - Nazi Culture, 1963-1981 (Box 42, Folder 19)
      - Grosset & Dunlap - Nazi Culture - Copyright Permissions, 1963-1981 (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - Grosset & Dunlap - Royalties, 1964-1983 (Box 42, Folder 21)
      - Group for Academic Freedom, 1950 (Box 42, Folder 22)
      - Gruppo di Studi Ebraici, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - Gustav Landauer Archive, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - Gustavus Adolphus College, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - Hadassah, 1992-1999 (Box 42, Folder 26)
      - Hampshire College, 1973 (Box 42, Folder 27)
      - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1966-1968, 1974 (Box 42, Folder 28)
      - HarperCollins (Firm), 1991-1998 (Box 42, Folder 29)
      - Harvard University, 1980, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 30)
      - Harvard University. Press., 1973, 1991-1997 (Box 42, Folder 31)
      - Hebrew Union College - Doctor of Humane Letters Degree, honoris causa, 1987 (Box 42, Folder 32)
      - Hebrew Union College. Efroymson Lectureship Committee, 1979-1982 (Box 42, Folder 33)
      - Hemisphere Publishing Corporation, 1986-1989 (Box 42, Folder 34)
      - Hillel, 1982, 1992-1993 (Box 42, Folder 35)
      - Histoire, 1995, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 36)
      - Historial de la Grande Guerre de Péronne, 1989-1996 (Box 42, Folder 37)
      - Historian, 1976, 1985-1986 (Box 42, Folder 38)
      - Historical Reflections, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 39)
      - History and Theory, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 40)
      - History Teacher, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 41)
      - Hochschule für Jüdische Studien Heidelberg, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 42)
      - Holocaust and Genocide Studies, 1998 (Box 42, Folder 43)
      - Holocaust Center of Greater Pittsburgh, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 44)
      - Holocaust Library and Research Center Associates of San Francisco, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 45)
      - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, Inc., 1950-1996 (Box 42, Folder 46)
      - Holt, Rinehart, and Winston, Inc. - Royalties, 1953-1994 (Box 42, Folder 47)
      - Homolulu, 1992 (Box 42, Folder 48)
      - Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 49)
      - Houghton, Mifflin and Company, 1981-1983, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 50)
      - Howard Fertig, 1973-1998 (Box 42, Folder 51)
      - Howard Fertig, Inc -Germans and Jews, 1965-1971 (Box 42, Folder 52)
      - Howard Fertig -Masses and Men, 1978-1981 (Box 42, Folder 53)
      - Howard Fertig -Nationalism and Sexuality, 1980-1984 (Box 42, Folder 54)
      - Howard Fertig -The Nationalization of the Masses, 1972-1989 (Box 42, Folder 55)
      - Huizinga Instituut, 1996-1997 (Box 42, Folder 56)
      - Humanities Press, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 57)
      - Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, 1996-1997 (Box 42, Folder 58)
      - Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin - Lectures, 1964-1965 (Box 42, Folder 59)
      - Indiana University, 1967, 1971-1972 (Box 42, Folder 60)
      - Indiana University. Press, 1983-1997 (Box 42, Folder 61)
      - Initiative HomoMonument, 1996-1997 (Box 42, Folder 62)
      - Institut für die Wissenschaften vom Menschen (Vienna, Austria), 1988 (Box 42, Folder 63)
      - Institute for Advanced Studies (Princeton, N.J.), 1995-1996 (Box 42, Folder 64)
      - Institute of Contemporary History and Wiener Library, 1988-1998 (Box 42, Folder 65)
      - Instituto della Enciclopedia Italiana, 1987, 1994, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Instituto di ricerche economiche e sociali (Rome, Italy), 1993 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Instituto Gramsci Toscano, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Instituto Italiano di Cultura (Stanford, Ca.), 1993 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Instituto Nazionale per la Storia del Movimento di Liberazione in Italia, 1992-1995 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Instituto Socialista di Studi Storici, 1971, 1977-1978 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - International Association of Historical Societies for the Study of Jewish History, 1994 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - International Commission for the History of Representative and Parliamentary Institutions, 1951-1953 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - International Commission on Historical Demography, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - International History Review, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - International Institute of Social History, 1965, 1988, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - International Lesbian and Gay Youth Organisation, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - International P.E.N. Books, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - Iowa Conference of University Professors, 1953-1955 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Isis, 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - Israel Film Archive, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Israel Science Foundation, 1993-1995 (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - J.M. Dent & Sons, 1973-1978 (Box 43, Folder 18)
      - Jerusalem Post, 1988-1990 (Box 43, Folder 19)
      - Jewish Community Center of Milwaukee, 1975-1980 (Box 43, Folder 20)
      - Jewish Museum (New York, N.Y.), 1984 (Box 43, Folder 21)
      - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1976-1981 (Box 43, Folder 22)
      - John Jay College of Criminal Justice. Center on Violence and Human Survival, 1989, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 23)
      - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1991-1997 (Box 43, Folder 24)
      - John Wiley and Sons, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 25)
      - Johns Hopkins University Press, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 26)
      - Joods Historisch Museum (Amsterdam, Netherlands), 1996 (Box 43, Folder 27)
      - Journal of History of Ideas, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 28)
      - Journal of Homosexuality, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 29)
      - Journal of Modern History, 1973-1975, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 30)
      - Journal of Psychohistory, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 31)
      - Judah L. Magnes Memorial Museum, 1995-1998 (Box 43, Folder 32)
      - Judah L. Magnes Memorial Museum - Stalin's Forgotten Israel Exhibit Draft, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 33)
      - Judaism - A Quarterly Journal of Jewish Life and Thought, 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 34)
      - Jüdische Volkshochschule Berlin, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 35)
      - Jüdischer Kulturverein Berlin, 1990-1997 (Box 43, Folder 36)
      - Jüdisches Museum Berlin, 2000, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 37)
      - Jüdisches Museum Frankfurt a.M., 1992 (Box 43, Folder 38)
      - Kashiwa Shobō Publishing Co., 1993-1996 (Box 43, Folder 39)
      - Kenneth B. Smilen/Present Tense Literary Award, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 40)
      - Kent State University, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 41)
      - King's College (University of London), 1973 (Box 43, Folder 42)
      - Klett-Cotta, 1991-1996 (Box 43, Folder 43)
      - Koninklijke Nederlandse Akademie van Wetenschappen. Commissie voor de geschiedenis van de joden in Nederland, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 44)
      - Kunstsammlung Nordrhein-Westfalen (Germany), 1986-1987 (Box 43, Folder 45)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (Jerusalem, Israel), 1971, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 46)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (London, England), 1960-1996 (Box 43, Folder 47)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (New York), 1956-1979 (Box 43, Folder 48)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (New York), 1980-1989 (Box 43, Folder 49)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (New York), 1990-1999 (Box 43, Folder 50)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (New York) - Honoring George Mosse, 1997-1998 (Box 43, Folder 51)
      - Leo Baeck Institute (New York) - Newsletters, 1975-1978, 1997-1999 (Box 43, Folder 52)
      - Library of Christian classics (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1961-1969 (Box 43, Folder 53)
      - Longman (Firm), 1960-1990 (Box 43, Folder 54)
      - Longman (Firm) - Royalty Statements, 1968-1988 (Box 43, Folder 55)
      - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1988-1991, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 56)
      - Macmillan Publishers, 1986, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 57)
      - Madison Jewish Community Council, 1992-1996 (Box 43, Folder 58)
      - Magnus-Hirschfeld-Gesellschaft, 1987?, 1993, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 59)
      - Melton Center for Jewish Studies (Ohio State University), 1995-1996 (Box 43, Folder 60)
      - Merkaz Zalman Shazar le-toldot Yi'sra'el, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 61)
      - Michigan State University Press, 1948-1979 (Box 43, Folder 62)
      - Milwaukee Jewish Council, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 63)